Jason Lengstorf: 我们在这里要做的最后一件事是添加对
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: The last thing we
wanna do here is actually add support for
对实体 API 运行查询并返回结果。
running queries against that brick and
mortar API and returning results.
为了做到这一点，我们首先要得到我们需要的依赖关系。
So to do that, we're gonna start out by
getting the dependencies that we need.
我们要利用阿波罗计划。
We're gonna be using Apollo for this.
Apollo 是一个 GraphQL 库，具有特定的 React 设置。
Apollo is a GraphQL library
that has specific React setup.
它的设计是相对简单的设置，他们只是
It's designed to be relatively
straightforward to set up and they just
释放钩子支持，这是真的，真的很好，所以我们要使用这个。
released hook support which is really,
really nice, so we're gonna use that.
所以我们要加纱盖茨比插件阿波罗和
So we're gonna yarn add
gatsby-plugin-apollo and
那我们就有依赖性了。
then we're gonna have some dependencies.
所以它需要 graphql 标签，然后它需要 apollo / react-common
So it needs the graphql tag and
then it needs apollo/react-common for
一些普通的部件，然后它需要 apollo / reaction-hooks
some common pieces will use, and
then it needs apollo/react-hooks for
我们要用的反应钩。
the react hooks that we want to use.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 所以我们将安装它。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So
we'll get that installed.
在我们等待安装的同时,
And while we're waiting for
that to install,
我将创建一个名为 results.js 的新组件。
I'm gonna create a new
component called results.js.
在它里面，我们要进口反应，从反应和
And inside of it we're gonna
import react from react and
我们还要从 apollo / react-hooks 进口电子设备。
we're also going to import
useQuery from apollo/react-hooks.
Jason Lengstorf: 我们将导入 gql 标记，它非常
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
we'll import the gql tag which is very
不同于盖茨比使用的石头。
different from the graphql
that Gatsby uses.
因为 GQL 标记，所以在这里进行区分是很重要的
And it's important to draw
a distinction here because the GQL tag
保留在代码中，所以这个会发送到浏览器。
stays in the code, so
this will ship to the browser.
当你写一个 GraphQL 查询时，它会告诉你,
And what it's doing is it's telling
when you write a GraphQL query,
使用模板标记时，GQL 标记将其分解
and you use that template tag,
the GQL tag breaks it down
一些 GraphQL 服务器可以理解的东西。
into something that a GraphQL
server can understand.
盖茨比 GraphQL 在构建时被删除，它标记的内容类似于,
The Gatsby GraphQL gets removed at build
time, it's marking something as like,
嘿，你应该在构建过程中处理这个。
hey, you should process
this during the build.
阿波罗公司的 GQL 正在告诉阿波罗如何解释已经写好的和
GQL from Apollo is telling Apollo how to
interpret a query that's been written and
在建造时间执行。
executed at build time.
这就是为什么它们是不同的东西，它们执行不同的功能。
So that's why they're different things,
they perform different functions.
但是如果您需要一个 GraphQL，那么它可能会有点混乱
But it can be a little confusing
especially if you need a GraphQL
了解每件作品的作用，以及它们的必要性。
to understand exactly what each of those
pieces does and why they're necessary.
但是这就是为什么它存在的快速版本。
But that's the very fast
version of why that's there.
所以我要做的第一件事就是设置我的搜索查询。
So the first thing I wanna do
is to set up my search query.
因为我们是为客户服务的,
And because we're doing
this on the client side,
我们可以使用任何我们想要的变量，我们可以做任何我们想做的事情。
we can use any variables that we want, we
can do really anything that we want here.
这是 Rick 和 Morty 的 API，我们将从我们想去的地方开始。
So this is the Rick and Morty API, and
we'll just start with where we want to be.
所以我们想对字符进行查询。
So we want to do a query for characters.
和 Morty API 使用了一个不同的 GraphQL Explorer。
The Rick and Morty API uses
a different GraphQL Explorer.
所以它有点不同，它没有喜欢点击按钮
So it's a little bit different, it doesn't
have the the like click button this
建立一个查询的东西，这是一种无赖，但它仍然很不错。
to build a query thing, which is kind of
a bummer, but it's still pretty nice.
我们要深入调查这里的医生看看。
So we're gonna dig into the docs
over here and take a look.
所以我们有了字符查询，这就是我想要的
So we've got the characters query,
which is what I want and
在里面，我可以设置一个过滤器。
inside of it, I can set a filter.
我想要的过滤器会出现在名字上。
And the filter that I want
is gonna be on the name.
让我们查询一下这个名字，它是一个字符串
So let's query on the name,
that's gonna be a string and
然后我想过滤的名称，我们会使用这个名称变量。
then I want to filter on the name and
we'll use that name variable.
所以我们可以在这里打开查询变量
So we may open up the query
variables down here and
我们会说这个名字是让我们先做瑞克。
we'll say that the name is
gonna be let's do Rick first.
然后，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 一旦我们进入这里,
Then,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Once we're in here,
我们可以点击 Option + Space 查看可用的字段是什么。
we can hit Option + Space to see
what the available fields are.
所以我要得到结果在我的结果里面,
So I'm gonna get results and
inside my results,
选项 + 空间再次，让我们只是得到的名称现在。
Option + Space again, and
let's just get the name for now.
所以我们应该让每个人都叫瑞克，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 还有
So we should get everybody named Rick,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
我们可以看到它们的数量不少。
we can see that there
are quite a few of them.
如果我们加入这些信息，我们可以看到我认为计数。
And if we were to include the info,
we can see I think the count.
所以这部剧里有73个叫 Rick 的角色
So there are 73 characters in the show
named Rick, and we are getting
一个子选项，不是所有的，但是对我们来说这个是可以的，对吗？
a sub-selection, it's not all of them,
but for our purposes this is okay, right?
所以让我们继续前进，得到所有我们需要的东西。
So let's go ahead and
get all the stuff that we need.
所以我认为，为了我们的目的，我们需要一个身份证明。
So I think for our purposes,
we're going to get an ID.
我们需要名字，让我们得到物种，将得到原产地名称,
We want the name, let's get the species,
will get the origin name,
我们会得到位置，然后我们会得到名字和尺寸。
and we'll get the location, and
we'll do the name and dimension for that.
最后，让我们抓取图像。
And then finally, let's grab the image.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，这将给我们我们要做的一切
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, and so this
will give us everything that we're gonna
需要显示一些结果，他们在哪里，他们从哪里来，名字和
need to show some results back where they
are, where they came from, name and and
这样我们就可以展示出来。
image of them so
that we can show that off.
既然知道了这一点，我们就可以把这个问题直接放到这里。
So knowing that, we can take this query
and we can drop it straight in here.
让我们把这个做小一点，好吗？
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And let's make
this a little bit smaller, okay?
所以我在这里有我的全部问题。
So I've got my full query up here.
然后，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我要设置我的
And then,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: I'm going to set up my
组件。
component.
所以我的组件将被称为结果，它将接受一个名字道具。
So my component is gonna be called Results
and it's going to accept a name prop.
这个名字就是结果
And that name prop is gonna be the result
我们要从 URL 中得到的查询。
of the query that we're
gonna get out of the URL.
那么，让我们首先开始查询。
So let's first, fire off the query.
所以 useQuery 的工作方式是我们发送查询本身,
So the way that useQuery works
is we send in the query itself,
我们已经在这里定义了，然后我们可以解析任何变量。
which we've defined up here, and
then we can parse in any variables.
所以我要传入的变量只是名字，所以这个放在这里。
So the variables that I'm gonna pass in
are just the name, so this goes into here.
我们要拿出来的是一个装载道具。
And what we're gonna get out
of it is a loading prop.
因此，在执行查询时，加载将为 true。
So when the query is executing,
loading will be true.
如果出了什么差错，我们就会得到一个错误。
If anything goes wrong,
we're gonna get an error.
如果一切顺利，我们就能得到数据。
And if everything goes well,
we'll get data.
一旦我们得到了结果，我们会检查是否有结果
Once we have that, we're gonna check
to see if we've got results and
我们可以这样说，如果有数据。
we can do that by just
saying if there's data.
然后我们要做一些很复杂的动作。
And then we're gonna do a little
bit of kind of like tricky stuff.
所以我们说数据字符长度，如果失败了,
So we'll say data characters length and
if that fails,
我们跳到一个空数组，然后设置长度
we're gonna just skip over to an empty
array, and then we'll set the length and
如果长度大于0就意味着我们得到了结果。
say if the length is greater than 0,
that means we have results.
所以基本上，如果数据返回为空，我们将显示没有结果。
So basically, if the data comes back
empty, we will show a no results.
或者如果出于某种原因我们根本没有一个角色道具
Or if if for some reason we don't
get a characters prop at all
将默认为空数组，然后显示没有结果。
will default to an empty array and
then show no results.
一旦我们知道了这些，我们就可以返回我们的对象。
Once we know about that,
we can return our object.
所以对于这本书，为了让它不至于无法阅读,
And so for this one, for the sake of
making it not impossible to read,
我们来做一些嵌入式样式。
we'll do a little bit of inline styling.
所以我们要设置一个最大宽度为500
So we're gonna set up
a max width of 500 and
然后我们在顶部设置一个50像素的边距
then we'll set up a margin
of 50 pixels at the top and
底部和中心左边和右边。
bottom and center it left and right.
然后我们会说这些是我们的搜索结果
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And then we'll say
that these are our search results, and
让我们看看，如果我们装载。
let's see, if we're loading.
我们只展示一个段落，说加载结果。
We're going to show just a paragraph
that says loading results.
如果有错误，我们将显示一个 pre-tag 和
If there is an error,
we will show a pre-tag and
我们只是要有 overflowX 滚动。
we are just gonna have
the overflowX scroll.
因此，如果我们得到一个长的错误，它不会打破我们的布局。
So if we get a long error,
it doesn't blow our layout.
然后我们就可以解决这个错误。
And then we will just stringify the error.
传递错误也是如此。
So will do JSON.stringify
passing the error.
这是一个函数的弦,
That's stringfies a function,
所以我们将错误作为第一个参数传入，第二个参数为 null
so we'll pass in the error as the first
argument, null is the second argument, and
2作为空格的数量来打破对象和美化它一点点。
2 as the number of spaces to break the
object up and prettify it up a little bit.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 假设我们没有错误,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
assuming we don't have an error,
我们要检查一下有没有结果。
we're gonna check if we have results.
如果我们有结果，我们将，杰森冷斯托夫: 地图
And if we have results we wil,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Map
所以 data.characters. results.map,
over our characters, so
data.characters.results.map,
这样我们就有了一个角色。
that'll give us a character.
我们可以设置一个 div，它有一个钥匙
And we can set up a div,
and that'll have a key
我们查询的字符 ID。
of the character ID that we queried for
that.
所以我们可以使用任何回到这里的 ID，名称空格，等等。
So we can just use anything that comes
back here the ID, names spaces, etc.
在这里设置一点样式，所以显示 flex
Set up a little bit of styling on this,
so display flex so
我们可以在线上展示一些东西，而不是一大堆粗糙的东西。
that we can kind of show things in
the line as opposed to a big gnarly stack.
然后我们会设置一点点的底部边距
And then we'll set a little
bit of margin bottom so
东西不是一起砸碎的。
that things aren't smashed together.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，那么，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们已经得到了那个 div。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, then,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We've got that div.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 是的，然后在这里我们需要弄清楚
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Right, and
then down here we need to figure out if
没有装载，也没有结果。
its not loading and
it doesn't have results.
所以如果没有结果也没有加载,
So if it doesn't have results and
it's not loading,
我们要展示的只是一个基本的没有字符发现
we're going to show just
a basic no characters found
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 名字。
matching,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Name.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 假设我们到了这里，我们有了 div 和
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So assuming we
get in here we've got our div and
我们想展示一下我们所拥有的。
we want to show off what we've got.
因此，让我们设置一个 div 来保存图像。
So let's set up a div to hold the image.
这个有点小问题，我觉得这个可以清理一下
And this is getting a little divy,
I think this could be cleaned up but
我们不是为了设计奖，我们是为了,
again we're not going for
design awards here, we're going for,
展示客户端应用程序是如何工作的。
showing how the client
side app would work.
所以如果你要这么做，请不要把你的标记弄得这么难看。
So if you go to do this,
please don't make your markup this ugly.
让我们来做一个图像，Jason Lengstorf: 在我们的
Let's go and do an image,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And inside of our
图片我们需要的来源，我们要使用的字符图片，这是一个网址。
image we need source and we're gonna
use the character.image which is a URL.
然后，我们要使用 alt，这是字符的名字,
Then, we're gonna use the alt,
which is the character's name,
和一点点的风格，我们会设置为100% 宽,
and a little bit of style,
we will set it to be 100% wide,
所以基本上填满这个 div。
so just fill this div basically.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 接下来，因为我们使用 flexbox，我们将,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And next to that,
because we're using flexbox, we will,
设置一个 h 3来显示,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Set up an h3 to show,
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 名字。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: The name.
所以我们会说 character.name 和
So we'll say character.name, and
让我们使字体大小20和设置边距顶部为0，所以
let's make the font size 20 and
set the margin top to 0 so
没有破坏整个布局。
that it's not blowing out the layout.
然后我们会建立一个物种
And then we'll set up a Species and
利用角色特征，物种特征。
use the character.species for that.
然后我们复制这个，然后说 Origin 和
And then let's duplicate this and
say Origin and
我们用 character.origin.name。
we'll use the character.origin.name.
我认为这可能是好的，让我们看看物种和起源的名称，所以
And I think that's probably good, so
let's see species and origin name, so
实际上我们不用这个位置，所以我们可以不用这个。
we're actually not using the location so
we can just drop that out.
那么让我们导出这个结果，Jason Lengstorf: 默认结果，好吗？
So let's export this result,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Default results, okay?